Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we're talking about a kind of education that is quite unique
我是Catherine，今天我们讨论一种相当独特的教育方式，
actually a little bit different from the kind of education that most people get.
实际上，它和大多数人接受的教育有点不同。
That's right.
没错。
So we normally go to school to learn but on this occasion we're going to talk about a
所以我们通常去学校学习，但这次我们要讨论一种
different way of obtaining your education.
不同的获取教育的方式。
We're talking about homeschooling someone.
我们说的是在家教育孩子。
Let's check this word out in today's vocabulary preview.
让我们在今天的词汇预览中看看这个词。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
Alright so the word is homeschool, to homeschool someone.
好的，这个词是homeschool，在家教育某人。
It's I guess a verb.
我想它是一个动词。
And what does it mean if you're homeschooled?
如果你在家接受教育，那意味着什么？
Well you think about the word school, home, it means that you study at home.
嗯，想想school和home这两个词，意思就是你在家学习。
But you don't go to school every day.
但你不用每天去学校。
Instead you have a parent or maybe a friend of a parent who comes to your house to teach
而是由父母或父母的朋友来你家
you every day.
每天教你。
So it's basically like having a tutor for but not to help you with school but to actually
所以基本上就像有个家教，但不是帮你补习学校功课，而是
teach you everything that you learn at school.
教你学校学的一切。
That's right and some people are homeschooled with their siblings, so brothers and sisters.
没错，有些人会和兄弟姐妹一起在家接受教育。
Other people are homeschooled alone.
其他人则独自在家学习。
We'll talk about some of these things in a moment but let's take a listen to our dialogue.
我们一会儿会讨论这些，但先来听听我们的对话。
I think we should homeschool our children when we decide to have kids.
我觉得我们决定要孩子后，应该在家教育他们。
What?
什么？
Why?
为什么？
Well our public schools here are not very good and private schools are just too expensive.
嗯，这里的公立学校不太好，私立学校又太贵。
I've been reading up on some homeschooling and it has a lot of advantages.
我一直在研究在家教育，它有很多优点。
Like what?
比如什么？
I think that by doing something like that we would be isolating our children from social
我觉得这样做会让孩子
interaction.
与社会互动隔绝。
Well first of all I would be able to teach them everything they learn in school in a
首先，我能以更轻松有趣的方式
more relaxed and fun way.
教他们学校学的一切。
I also think that having a one-on-one class is much better since you can focus more on
我还觉得一对一教学更好，因为可以更专注于
his or her strengths or weaknesses.
他或她的优点或弱点。
I think neither your parents or mine would agree to such an idea.
我觉得你父母或我父母都不会同意这种想法。
I'll bring it up over Sunday brunch.
我会在周日早午餐时提出来。
Good luck with that.
祝你好运。
All right we're back so now let's take a look at some of that language on Language
好了，我们回来了，现在来看看“语言要点”中的
Takeaway.
一些语言点。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
So as we mentioned in the introduction to today's podcast, homeschooling is one of many
正如我们在今天播客介绍中提到的，在家教育是众多
different educational options.
不同教育选择之一。
The most common ones are, in the beginning of the dialogue, public and private school.
最常见的是对话开头提到的公立和私立学校。
So in most places you will have public schools where basically the education is paid for
所以在大多数地方，有公立学校，基本上教育费用
by the government.
由政府支付。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
So public schools are schools that are available to all students.
所以公立学校是对所有学生开放的学校。
You don't have to pay to attend them.
你不需要付费就能上学。
This is of course in America.
这当然是在美国。
In Britain the system is a bit different.
在英国，系统有点不同。
But in America you have the public schools which most kids go to.
但在美国，有大多数孩子去的公立学校。
Of course if your parents don't want you to study in public school there's another option
当然，如果父母不想让孩子上公立学校，还有另一种选择，
that's called private school.
叫做私立学校。
That's right.
没错。
Private school as the name says, it's not really private but what happens is that it's
私立学校，顾名思义，不是真的“私密”，而是
not available free for everyone.
不是免费对所有人开放。
You have to actually pay to go to the school.
你必须付费才能上学。
That's right.
没错。
The school has a tuition, kind of like a private college or university.
学校有学费，有点像私立学院或大学。
So you have to pay every semester or every year.
所以每学期或每年都要付钱。
And usually these schools also have application standards.
而且这些学校通常还有申请标准。
So they interview you, they interview your parents.
所以他们会面试你，面试你的父母。
So there's a lot of different things you have to do to attend these schools.
所以上这些学校要做很多不同的事情。
So they're a bit more exclusive.
所以它们更排外一些。
That's right.
没错。
So these are basically some three options you have.
所以基本上你有这三种选择。
Homeschooling, public schools, private schools.
在家教育、公立学校、私立学校。
And well the two parents are kind of discussing the options of why it would be maybe not a
嗯，两位父母在讨论为什么在家教育孩子
good idea to homeschool one of the kids.
可能不是个好主意。
And she says that it would be isolating our children from social interaction.
她说这会“让孩子与社会互动隔绝”。
Alright.
好的。
So let's take a look at the word to isolate.
让我们看看“isolate”这个词。
This is a verb.
这是一个动词。
And I like to think of island, isolate, kind of similar in a way.
我喜欢把island（岛屿）和isolate（隔绝）联系起来，有点相似。
Basically to isolate from is to keep away from.
基本上，“isolate from”意思是远离。
So if your student or your child is being homeschooled, he or she might be isolated
所以如果你的学生或孩子在家接受教育，他或她可能会
from other students.
与其他学生隔绝。
They're not near or with other students.
他们不接近或与其他学生在一起。
That's right.
没错。
So to isolate means to keep away from or to keep separately.
所以“isolate”意思是远离或分开。
So like you said, maybe if you're on an island, you are isolated from the rest of the world.
就像你说的，也许如果你在岛上，你就与世界其他地方隔绝了。
That's right.
没错。
I live in the country far away from the city.
我住在远离城市的乡下。
I feel isolated from other people.
我觉得自己与其他人隔绝了。
So she's saying that the kid might be isolated from social interaction.
所以她说这个孩子可能被隔离于社交互动之外。
Alright.
好的。
Now, social interaction.
现在，社交互动。
This is a two-word phrase.
这是一个由两个词组成的短语。
We usually take it as a phrase.
我们通常把它当作一个短语来理解。
This basically means talking to or playing with other people, other kids.
这基本上意味着与他人、其他孩子交谈或玩耍。
Right.
对。
So I guess in this case, it's personal or physical social interaction because nowadays
所以我想在这种情况下，它指的是个人或面对面的社交互动，因为如今
we have social interaction via the internet.
我们通过互联网进行社交互动。
That's right.
没错。
But in the case of a student going to school, it would be of course playing on the playground,
但就学生上学而言，当然包括在操场上玩耍、
attending class.
上课。
But social interaction means talking to or being with other people.
但社交互动意味着与他人交谈或相处。
That's right.
没错。
Well, and the other parent argued that there are many advantages and specifically he said
嗯，另一位家长辩称有很多好处，他特别提到
that having a one-on-one class is better for the kids.
一对一上课对孩子更好。
Alright, so this word one-on-one refers to one teacher, one student.
好了，所以这个词“一对一”指的是一个老师、一个学生。
Right.
对。
One parent, one child.
一个家长、一个孩子。
It means when you're talking to someone and there's no one else around.
意思是当你和某人交谈时，周围没有其他人。
Alright, so usually tutors teach you one-on-one.
好了，所以通常家教是给你一对一上课。
You sit at a table and your tutor helps you study.
你坐在桌子旁，家教帮你学习。
But in the case of homeschooling, the student learns one-on-one.
但在家庭教育的情况下，学生是一对一学习。
So learns directly from the teacher.
所以是直接从老师那里学习。
Right, and that's different from public schools obviously because you have one teacher for
对，这显然和公立学校不同，因为公立学校是一个老师教
maybe 30 students.
可能三十个学生。
That's right.
没错。
So that's one-on-one.
所以那就是一对一。
That's one-on-many.
那是一对多。
Right, exactly.
对，完全正确。
But one-on-one is also a word you can use when you talk about meetings.
但“一对一”这个词也可以用在谈论会议时。
So you could say, hey Marco, can we have a one-on-one meeting later?
所以你可以说，嘿，Marco，我们待会儿能开个一对一会议吗？
I'd like to talk to you alone.
我想单独和你谈谈。
So that means I'm not going to talk to you with other people around.
所以那意味着我不会在其他人面前和你说话。
Right, okay, it's like a private meeting.
对，好的，就像是个私人会议。
Yeah.
嗯。
Very good.
非常好。
So let's take a listen to the dialogue again and then we're going to come back and we're
那么，让我们再听一遍对话，然后回来看看一些关键短语。
going to take a look at some key phrases.
我们将要看看一些关键短语。
I think we should homeschool our children when we decide to have kids.
我觉得等我们决定要孩子的时候，应该在家教育他们。
What?
什么？
Why?
为什么？
Well, our public schools here are not very good and private schools are just too expensive.
嗯，我们这里的公立学校不太好，私立学校又太贵了。
I have been reading up on some homeschooling and it has a lot of advantages.
我一直在研究在家教育，它有很多好处。
Like what?
比如什么？
I think that by doing something like that we would be isolating our children from social
我觉得这样做的话，我们会让孩子失去社交互动。
interaction.
社交互动。
Well, first of all, I would be able to teach them everything they learn in school in a
嗯，首先，我能用一种更轻松有趣的方式教他们学校里学的一切。
more relaxed and fun way.
用一种更轻松有趣的方式。
I also think that having a one-on-one class is much better since you can focus more on
我还觉得一对一的教学更好，因为可以更专注于他或她的优点或缺点。
his or her strengths or weaknesses.
他或她的优点或缺点。
I think neither your parents or mine would agree to such an idea.
我觉得你父母或我父母都不会同意这种想法。
I'll bring it up over Sunday brunch.
我会在周日早午餐时提出来。
Good luck with that.
祝你好运。
All right, we've picked out four key phrases for you today.
好了，今天我们为你挑选了四个关键短语。
Let's take a look at those on Fluency Builder.
让我们在流利度构建器上看看这些。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
So the first phrase today in Fluency Builder is the phrase to read up on.
所以今天流利度构建器中的第一个短语是“to read up on”。
So the sentence was, I've been reading up on homeschooling and it has a lot of advantages.
所以句子是：我一直在研究在家教育，它有很多优点。
Right.
对。
So basically if you say you have been reading up on a subject or a topic or something, it
所以基本上，如果你说你一直在研究某个主题或话题，那
means that you've been reading about it, you've kind of been informing yourself.
意味着你一直在阅读相关内容，你一直在给自己充电。
You're doing research about a topic.
你在做关于某个话题的研究。
So in this case, one parent is researching the homeschooling option.
所以在这个例子中，一位家长正在研究在家教育的选项。
So here she is reading maybe articles in a magazine or books or looking on the internet.
所以她可能是在读杂志文章、书籍，或者上网查资料。
But you don't actually just have to read up on education.
但你实际上不一定只研究教育。
You can read up on anything, right?
你可以研究任何东西，对吧？
Right.
对。
Exactly.
没错。
So you can read up on anything that interests you or you can do research on anything.
所以你可以研究任何你感兴趣的东西，或者做任何方面的研究。
So you can read up on dinosaurs, for example.
比如，你可以研究恐龙。
I've been reading up on dinosaurs lately.
我最近一直在研究恐龙。
And did you know that the brontosaurus is not a real dinosaur anymore?
你知道吗，雷龙现在已经不是真正的恐龙了？
That's right.
没错。
Okay, so we've been reading up on the advantages of homeschooling and he starts by, well, defending
好的，所以我们一直在研究在家教育的优点，而他开始用这个短语来
his position on what the advantages are with the phrase.
捍卫他对这些优点的立场。
Well, first of all.
嗯，首先呢。
All right.
好的。
This is an important little phrase.
这是一个重要的小短语。
This is something you can use, like you say, Marco, when you're going to have an argument
这是一个你可以用的表达，就像你说的，Marco，当你准备进行一场争论时，
or maybe a discussion about something and you want to tell your points, your side of
或者可能讨论某件事，你想表达你的观点、你的立场时，
the argument.
争论中的立场。
And so first of all means I have a list, but this is my first point.
所以 first of all 的意思是，我有一个列表，但这是我的第一点。
Right.
对。
So it's a nice little phrase to open up this list of things that you're going to say, right?
所以这是一个很好的小短语，用来开启你要说的一系列内容，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So you should drink orange juice, Marco, because first of all, it tastes good, but second of
所以你应该喝橙汁，Marco，因为首先，它味道好，但其次，
all, or, but also it's very good for your body.
或者说，而且它对你的身体也很好。
Right.
对。
So first of all is the first main point.
所以 first of all 是第一个主要观点。
So you can say second of all.
所以你可以说 second of all。
Can you go like third of all, fourth of all?
能说 third of all、fourth of all 吗？
Not really, right?
不太行，对吧？
You don't really say it.
你一般不会这么说。
I guess you could, but.
我想也许可以，但……
So you go first of all, second of all, and then maybe just go and also.
所以你会说 first of all、second of all，然后可能就直接说 and also。
Or lastly.
或者 lastly。
And then lastly to end it.
然后用 lastly 来结束。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
Now, one of the other points that he talked about, well, apart from the one-on-one class
现在，他提到的另一个点，除了一对一课程之外，
was that the reason why a one-on-one class was better is because he could focus on his
就是一对一课程更好的原因，是因为他可以专注于他或她的优点和/或缺点。
or her strengths and or weaknesses.
优点和/或缺点。
All right.
好的。
So strengths or weaknesses or strengths and weaknesses.
所以是 strengths or weaknesses 或者 strengths and weaknesses。
This is a set phrase.
这是一个固定短语。
And it's important to remember that these two words are opposites.
记住这两个词是反义词很重要。
So strengths, that's the things you're good at.
所以 strengths，就是你擅长的事情。
And weaknesses.
而 weaknesses。
Things you're bad at.
你不擅长的事情。
And so, especially when you're studying in a school or you're homeschooling, it's important
所以，尤其是当你在学校学习或在家自学时，老师了解学生的优点和缺点很重要。
that the teacher understands the strengths and weaknesses of the student.
因为对于你真正擅长的事情，也许应该鼓励，而对于你不擅长的事情，你应该更努力去改进。
Because something that you're really good at, maybe you should encourage and something
没错。
you're bad at, you should work harder at improving.
所以这通常是一个固定短语。
That's right.
没错。
So it's usually fixed phrase.
你甚至在求职面试中也会遇到。
You'll even get it in job interviews.
有人会说，嗯，你认为你的优点和缺点是什么？
Somebody will say, well, what do you think are your strengths and weaknesses?
对。
Right.
So remember that phrase, strengths and weaknesses.
所以记住这个短语，strengths and weaknesses。
Okay.
好的。
And lastly, he said that, well, even though the idea is interesting, it might be difficult
最后，他说，嗯，尽管这个想法很有趣，但可能很难让父母或祖父母同意他。
to make the parents or the grandparents agree with him.
所以他说他会在周日早午餐时提出来。
So he said he will bring it up over Sunday brunch.
好的。
Okay.
我会提出来。
I will bring it up.
提出来。
Bring it up.
Well, you're not actually holding something.
嗯，你实际上不是拿着什么东西。
This means that you will mention it in conversation.
这意味着你会在谈话中提到它。
Mention the topic, right?
提到这个话题，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So maybe grandma and grandpa don't think homeschooling is a good idea, but you will discuss it or
所以也许爷爷奶奶认为在家自学不是个好主意，但你会在周日早午餐时讨论它或
you will suggest it during Sunday brunch.
提出建议。
Right.
对。
So if you want to discuss a topic, you usually say, I will bring it up with the president,
所以如果你想讨论一个话题，你通常会说，我会向总统提出来，
for example.
比如。
That's right.
没错。
You will talk about it with the president.
你会和总统谈论这件事。
You can also say, please don't bring it up.
你也可以说，请别提出来。
Right.
对。
So maybe you told a secret and you don't want the other person to know and you say, okay,
所以也许你告诉了一个秘密，你不想让另一个人知道，然后你说，好的，
please Marco, don't bring it up.
请 Marco，别提出来。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
All right.
好的。
Let's listen to our dialogue one last time.
让我们最后听一遍我们的对话。
I think we should homeschool our children when we decide to have kids.
我觉得当我们决定要孩子时，应该在家自学他们。
What?
什么？
Why?
为什么？
Well, our public schools here are not very good and private schools are just too expensive.
嗯，我们这里的公立学校不太好，私立学校又太贵了。
I have been reading up on some homeschooling and it has a lot of advantages.
我一直在阅读一些关于在家自学的资料，它有很多优点。
Like what?
比如什么？
I think that by doing something like that, we would be isolating our children from social
我觉得这样做，我们会让孩子与社会隔绝开来。
interaction.
社会互动。
Well, first of all, I would be able to teach them everything they learn in school in a
嗯，首先，我可以教他们在学校学的一切，在一个
more relaxed and fun way.
更轻松、更有趣的方式。
I also think that having a one-on-one class is much better since you can focus more on
我也觉得一对一课程更好，因为你可以更专注于
his or her strengths or weaknesses.
他或她的优点或缺点。
I think neither your parents or mine would agree to such an idea.
我觉得你父母或我父母都不会同意这种想法。
I'll bring it up over Sunday brunch.
我会在周日早午餐时提出来。
Good luck with that.
祝你好运。
Okay.
好的。
So homeschooling is a very interesting option.
所以在家教育是一个非常有趣的选择。
I think it's very common, more common nowadays in Britain and North America.
我觉得这在英国和北美越来越常见了。
But how do people that are homeschooled go to college if they didn't go to a high school?
但是在家上学的人如果没上高中，怎么上大学呢？
Well, I believe that most people when they finish homeschooling will take some tests
嗯，我相信大多数人在完成在家教育后会参加一些考试，
to prove that they've actually learned the material that is required by the state.
来证明他们确实学到了州里要求的内容。
Because, you know, in America, each state sets the educational standards.
因为，你知道，在美国，每个州都设定教育标准。
And so it's important that you learn certain science and math skills.
所以学习一定的科学和数学技能很重要。
And then once you take those tests, you would get your GED, your graduate diploma.
然后一旦你通过那些考试，就能拿到GED，也就是毕业文凭。
And that means that you've learned everything that a high school student should know.
这意味着你学到了所有高中生应该知道的东西。
Right.
对。
So it's interesting because it would seem a little bit strange to not want your kid
所以这很有趣，因为不想让孩子
to go to school.
去上学似乎有点奇怪。
But at the same time, there are many reasons why parents don't want their kids to go to
但与此同时，家长不想让孩子去上学
school.
有很多原因。
Like in this dialogue, maybe the schools are not really good or too expensive.
就像这段对话里说的，可能是学校不太好或者太贵。
What do you think about homeschooling?
你对在家教育怎么看？
Would you send your kids to homeschool?
你会送孩子去在家上学吗？
I don't think I would do homeschooling because I think it's really important for students
我觉得我不会选择在家教育，因为我认为学生
to or for children to learn how to get along with others and to learn to negotiate and
或者说孩子学会与他人相处、学会协商、
to learn to play and to also learn to respect their teachers because you have a different
学会玩耍、学会尊重老师非常重要，因为你和父母的关系
relationship with your parents than you do your teachers.
与你和老师的关系不同。
And I think there's a lot of valuable social lessons you can learn at school.
而且我觉得在学校能学到很多宝贵的社会经验。
But I do understand why a lot of people choose this option, especially if the schools in
但我确实理解为什么很多人选择这个选项，尤其是如果
their area are poor performing schools so that the students aren't learning enough.
他们所在地区的学校表现不佳，学生学不到足够的东西。
Or if maybe they're not safe because some schools there's some bullying or there's some
或者可能学校不安全，因为有些学校存在欺凌或
violence.
暴力。
And so for those reasons, I definitely understand the motivation to do homeschooling.
所以出于这些原因，我完全理解选择在家教育的动机。
But then again, you can't.
但话说回来，你不能。
I mean, you can get homeschooled from kindergarten all the way through high school, right?
我的意思是，你可以从幼儿园一直到高中都在家上学，对吧？
But there is no homeschooling for university unless you do like an online degree or something
但大学没有在家教育，除非你读在线学位或
like that.
类似的东西。
You can't really be homeschooled for college.
你不能真的在家上大学。
No, there's distance courses so you could use the internet and learn online.
不，有远程课程，你可以用互联网在线学习。
But no, you can't homeschool for university.
但不行，你不能在家上大学。
It's a very debatable topic.
这是一个很有争议的话题。
A lot of people defend it saying it's good.
很多人为它辩护，说它很好。
It brings parents closer together to their kids, that kids enjoy learning, that they
它让父母和孩子更亲近，孩子喜欢学习，
learn better, etc.
学得更好等等。
Other people don't really agree with it.
其他人则不太同意。
So what is your opinion?
那么你的看法是什么？
Do you agree with homeschooling?
你同意在家教育吗？
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
We hope to hear your arguments there.
我们期待在那里听到你的论点。
Okay, we'll see you there.
好的，我们那里见。
Bye.
再见。
수가